Curt Stern Papers 1907-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.5
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 1907-1981 (Box 1-43)
  - Stern, C. and Calvin B. Bridges. "The mutants of the extreme left end of the second chromosome of Drosophila melanogaster", 1926; 4 folders (Box 38)
    - Folder 2, 1926; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 3, 1926; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 4, 1926; 1 item (Box 38)
  - Stern, C. and Trudy Enders. "The frequency of twin births in relation to the age of the mother", 1947-1948; 3 folders (Box 38)
    Human genetics -- Twins; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Research data
    - Folder 1, 1947-1948; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 2, 1948; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 3, 1948; 1 item (Box 38)
  - Stern, C. and Sui Tong Fund. "Seriation of fourth chromosome loci in Drosophila Inelarogast", 1951; 1 folder (Box 38)
    Drosophila genetics; Publication; Sturtevant, Alfred Henry; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, C. and Gertrude Heidenthal. "Materials for study of position effect of normal and mutant genes", 1944; 1 folder (Box 38)
  - Stern, C. and Gertrude Heidenthal. "The position effect at the locus cubitus interruptus in Drosophila Melanogaster", 3 folders (Box 38)
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 38)
  - Stern, C. and Masuo Kodani. "Studies on position effect at the cubitus interruptus locus of Drosophila Melanogaster", 1954; 9 folders (Box 38)
    Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Research data
    - Folder 1, 1954; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 2, 1954; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 3, 1954; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 4, 1954; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 5, 1954; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 6, 1954; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 7, 1954; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 8, 1954; 1 item (Box 38)
    - Folder 9, 1954; 1 item (Box 38)
  - Stern, C. and Eva R. Sherwood. "Chromosome IV and sex balance in Drosophila Melanogaster", 1968; 2 folders (Box 38)
    Drosophila genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Research data
    - Folder 1, 1968; 4 items (Box 38)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 38)
  - Stern, C. and Chiyoko Tokunaga. "Non-autonomy of a pattern-determinig gene in mosaics of Drosophila", 1965; 5 items (Box 38)
  - Stern, Evelyn (Mrs. Curt Stern), 1924-1973; 2 folders (13 items) (Box 38)
    Biographical and personal data; Memorabilia
    - Folder 1, 1970-1973; 3 items (Box 38)
    - Folder 2, 1924; 8 items (Box 38)
  - Stern, Evelyn (Mrs. Curt Stern). Biography, 1955; 2 items (Box 38)
  - Stern, Hilde, 1948-1972; 3 items (Box 38)
  - Stern, Holly, 1948; 2 items (Box 38)
  - Stern, Kurt, 1931-`932; 2 items (Box 38)
  - Stern, Kurt G., 1941; 2 items (Box 38)
  - Stevens, F. E., 1959; 2 items (Box 38)
  - Stewart, Alice, 1960-1961; 4 items (Box 38)
  - Steyaert, Thomas A., 1973; 1 item (Box 38)
  - Stich, H. F., 1968; 3 items (Box 39)
  - Stiles, William W., 1954; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Stokinger, Herbert E., 1967; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Stone, Frederick Logan, 1944-1969; 6 items (Box 39)
  - Stone, Lois C., 1968; 4 items (Box 39)
  - Stone, William H., 1967; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Stone, Wilson S., 1964; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Stone, Wilson S. Memorial Fund, 1968; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Stormont, Clyde, 1959; 7 items (Box 39)
  - Straub, J., 1958-1967; 6 items (Box 39)
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 1953-1958; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Streit, Clarence, 1947; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Strohman, Richard C., 1969; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Stromberg, LaWayne R., 1966; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Stromnaes, Oistein, 1961; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Stubbe, A. E., 1941-1964; 5 items (Box 39)
  - Stubbe, Hans, 1964-1973; 6 items (Box 39)
  - Stubbe, Hans (letter to Richard Goldschmidt, July 27, 1951), 1 item (Box 39)
  - Stumpf, Hildegard, 1963; 3 items (Box 39)
  - Sturtevant, Alfred H., 1927-1968; 3 folders (Box 39)
    Alava, Aloha Margaret Hannah; Biographical and personal data; Bridges, Calvin B.; California Institute of Technology; Castle, William Ernest; Columbia University; Displaced German scholars; Dobzhansky, Theodosius; Drosophila genetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Human genetics; MacKnight, Robert H.; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; Miller, Dwight D.; Morgan, Thomas Hunt; Political issues; Referee's report; Schultz, Jack; Travel -- England; Wright, Sewall
    - Folder 1, 1927-1930; 9 items (Box 39)
    - Folder 2, 1933-1947; 20 items (Box 39)
    - Folder 3, 1949-1968; 24 items (Box 39)
  - Sturtevant, Alfred H. (letter to Roy E. Clausen, August 27, 1927), 1 item (Box 39)
  - Sturtevant, Alfred H. (Mrs.), 1928-1970; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Summerlin, William T., 1970; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Surrarrer, T. C., 1969; 5 items (Box 39)
  - Sussman, M., 1960; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Sutton, D., 1971; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Sutton, Eileen, 1943-1944; 11 items (Box 39)
  - Sutton, H. Eldon, ? items (Box 39)
  - Sutton, H. Eldon. "Monitoring somatic mutations", 1970; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Suzuki, David, 1969-1970; 6 items (Box 39)
  - Swanson, David L., 1966-1969; 3 items (Box 39)
  - Swanson, David L. "Genes and Development---A Study Using Scute Bristle Patterns in the Head Region of Mosaic Drosophila Melanogaster", 1956; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Swift, Hewson, 1954; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Swinyard, Chester A., 1967; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Symposium, 1971; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Symposium. International Symposium on Human Genetics (India, 1971), 1970-1971; 7 items (Box 39)
  - Symposium. L. J. Stadler Genetics Symposium (Third; Columbia, Missouri, 1971), 1 item (Box 39)
  - Symposium. Mendel Memorial Symposium (Brno and Prague, Czechoslovakia, 1965), 1964-1965; 3 items (Box 39)
  - Szabo, George, 1965; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Szilard, Leo, 1964; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Szuba, Zdzislaw, 1966; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Szulman, Aron E., 1970; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tackholm, Vivi, 1968; 3 items (Box 39)
  - Tadjoedin, M. K., 1965; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Takahara, Shigeo, 1969; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Takaya, H., 1971; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Talbot, T. R., Jr., 1972-1973; 5 items (Box 39)
  - Tammes, Tine, 1932; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tan, C. C., 1946-1947; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Tanaka, Katumi, 1952-1973; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Tandon, K. N., 1970; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Tanner, J. M. to A. L. deGaray, 1967; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tantawy, Azim O., 1971; 7 items (Box 39)
  - Tarbell, Stan, 1947; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tartof, Kenneth D., 1973; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Taylor, Kenneth M., 1959; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tazima, Yataro, 1966; 3 items (Box 39)
  - Teich, M., 1966; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Terry, Luther L., 1966 (ca); 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tëtry, Andreë (letter to R. Goldschmidt, ca. 1950 May (in French; re: F. Cuënot), 1 item (Box 39)
  - Thiessen, Delbert D., 1970; 3 items (Box 39)
  - Thoday, J. M., 1969; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Thomas, Cecil, 1958; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Thompson, David H., 1932-1933; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Thompson, Peter E., 1961-1969; 4 items (Box 39)
  - Thorslund, Stefan, 1961; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Thurstone, L. L., 1951; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tihen, Joe A., 1956; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tillinghast, Barbara Wilson, 1967; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Time (magazine), 1946; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Tischler, Georg, 1930; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tjio, J. H., 1960-1961; 3 items (Box 39)
  - Tobias, Cornelius A., 1952-1968; 3 items (Box 39)
  - Tobler, Heinz, 1964; 2 items (Box 39)
  - Todd, James, 1971; 10 items (Box 39)
  - Tokunaga, Chiyoko, 1956-1975; 26 items (Box 39)
    Drosophila genetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; Japan; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Tokunaga, Chiyoko. "Genetic mosaic studies...the classic prepattern hypothesis", n.d.; 3 folders (Box 39)
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 39)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 39)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tokunaga, Chiyoko and John C. Gerhart. "During the early period of Drosophila genetics...", 1976; 1 item (Box 39)
    Drosophila genetics
  - Tokunaga, Chiyoko and John C. Gerhart. "Effect of Growth and Joint Formation on Bristle Pattern", 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 39)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 39)
  - Tokunaga, Matsuno and Chikata Tokunaga, 1962-1965; 9 items (Box 40)
  - Tolarová, Marie, 1966; 2 items (Box 40)
  - Tolksdorf, Marlis, 1966; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Tomiyama, Itiro, 1972; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Tomlinson, Jack, 1968; 3 items (Box 40)
  - Tonomuro, A., 1969; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Torrey, Harry B., 1955; 3 items (Box 40)
  - Tower, W. L. (copies of letters, 1965 June, to A. Sokoloff from L. C. Dunn, A. H. Sturtevant, and Sewall Wright), 3 items (Box 40)
  - Tracey, Martin L., 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 40)
  - Traut, H., 1965; 2 items (Box 40)
  - Trembley, F. J., 1966; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Trend of Scottish Intelligence (notes; Univ. of London Pr., 1949), 1949-1955; 2 items (Box 40)
  - Trotter, Mildred, 1958; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Trusch, Norma, 1966; 3 items (Box 40)
  - Tschermak-Seysenegg, Erich von, 1949-1951; 2 folders (Box 40)
    Mendel, Gregor; Publication; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 1 item (Box 40)
    - Folder 2, 1949-1951; 6 items (Box 40)
  - Tsubaki, Kozi, 1960-1961; 5 items (Box 40)
  - Tuddenham, Read D., 1969; 2 items (Box 40)
  - Tunney, John, 1972; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Turpin, Raymond, 1961-1968; 2 items (Box 40)
  - Turtty, Victor, 1941; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Tweedell, Kenyon S., 1968; 2 items (Box 40)
  - Ubisch, V., 1948; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Uchida, Irene A., 1962-1969; 8 items (Box 40)
  - Ueno, Shokichi, 1973; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Ulrich, Hans, 1956; 2 items (Box 40)
  - Ulrich, W., 1953; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Ulrichs, Mrs. Cole, 1972; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Umeya, Y., 1948; 1 item (Box 40)
  - UNESCO. Statement on Race and Racial Prejudice, 1968; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Unger-Meyer, Helen, 1947; 3 items (Box 40)
  - Unidentified, n.d.; 2 items (Box 40)
  - U.S.S.R. Diary (Box 40)
    See Stone: USSR Exchange Visit
  - U.S.S.R. Society for Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries, 1943; 1 item (Box 40)
  - Unitarian Laymen's League, 1936; 1 item (Box 40)
  - United Nations. Seminar on Use of Vital and Health Statistics for Genetic and Radiation Studies, 1960; 1 item (Box 40)
  - U.S. Army Service Forces. Medical Division, 1944-1946; 8 items (Box 40)
  - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1950-1968; 21 items (Box 40)
    Atomic Energy Commission -- Reports; Committee activities -- Advisory Committee for Biology and Medicine; Honors -- Lawrence Award; Human genetics; Radiation genetics; Reviews -- Grobman, Arnold B.
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare. Public Health Service, National Institutes of Health, 1965; 3 items (Box 40)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare. Public Health Service, National Institutes of Health, Section on Epidemiology and Genetics, 1965; 2 items (Box 40)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare. Public Health Service, U.S.-Soviet Health Exchange, 1965; 1 item (Box 40)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1947; 1 item (Box 40)
  - U.S. War Department. Office of Chief of Ordnance, 1947; 3 items (Box 40)
  - Friedrich Wilhelms Universität, 1927-1932; 9 items (Box 40)
  - University College London, 1955; 1 item (Box 40)
  - "University Explorer" (radio program, University of California, 1950), 4 folders (Box 40)
    - Folder 1, 1950; 29 items (Box 40)
    - Folder 2, 1950; 35 items (Box 40)
    - Folder 3, 1950; 21 items (Box 40)
    - Folder 4, 1950; 27 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1958; 1 item (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Bancroft Library, Archives, 1968-1975; 4 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Biology Council Committee, 1965; 1 item (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Centennial, "A Century of Scientific Discovery", 1967-1968; 26 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Center for Research and Development in Higher Education, 1969; 2 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Committee on Drama, Lectures and Music, 1957; 1 item (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Committee on Grants and Contract Research, 1960; 5 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Constance, Lincoln, 1957-1959; 8 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Dept. of Genetics, 1956-1960; 10 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Dept. of Genetics - History, n.d.; 1 item (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Dept. of Zoology, 1947-1976; 2 folders (Box 40)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Research support; Teaching; University of California, Berkeley -- Department of Zoology; Zoology
    - Folder 1, 1947-1965; 19 items (Box 40)
    - Folder 2, 1973-1976; 22 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Dept. of Zoology - Directory 1975-76, 1975-1976; 1 item (Box 40)
    University of California, Berkeley -- Department of Zoology
  - University of California, Berkeley. Dept. of Zoology - Sigma Xi Nominations, 1964; 1 item (Box 40)
    Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Sigma Xi; University of California, Berkeley -- Department of Zoology
  - University of California, Berkeley. Division of Genetics, 1947; 2 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Eakin, Richard, 1956; 7 items (Box 40)
    Genetics; Invitations -- Stern, Curt; University of California, Berkeley; Zoology
  - University of California, Berkeley. Electron Microscope Committee, 1968; 2 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Institute for Basic Research in Science, 1960; 1 item (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Insurance and retirement systems, 1962; 2 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Kerr, Clark, 1961-1966; 11 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Loyalty Oath, 1950; 16 items (Box 40)
    Academic freedom; Political issues -- Loyalty oaths; University of California, Berkeley
  - University of California, Berkeley. Sproul, Robert, 1951-1959; 10 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Berkeley (?). Zoology staff, 1962-1970; 2 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, Los Angeles. Radio-Television Admin., 1965; 2 items (Box 40)
  - University of California Press, 1963-1971; 10 items (Box 40)
  - University of California, San Francisco. Comm. on Genetic Counselling, 1972; 1 item (Box 40)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1958; 1 item (Box 41)
  - University of Miami. Institute of Molecular Evolution, 1966; 2 items (Box 41)
  - University of Michigan. Department of Human Genetics - Bibliography, 1975; 1 item (Box 41)
  - University of Missouri. Department of Biology, 1967; 2 items (Box 41)
  - University of Missouri, Columbia. Department of Genetics, 1969; 2 items (Box 41)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Department of Zoology, 1965-1966; 5 items (Box 41)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1948; 1 item (Box 41)
  - University of Rochester, 1945-1947; 5 folders (Box 41)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Committee activities; Educational matters; University of Rochester -- Department of Biology; University of Rochester -- Department of Zoology
    - University of Rochester. Committee on Department of Biology, 1969-1970; 6 items (Box 41)
    - University of Rochester. Department of Zoology (Genetics equipment), 1947; 2 items (Box 41)
    - University of Rochester. Division of Biological Sciences - Report 1945, 1 item (Box 41)
    - University of Rochester. Science questionnaire (answers), 1947; 1 item (Box 41)
    - University of Rochester. Stern's resignation, 1946-1947; 5 items (Box 41)
  - University of Washington. Department of Botany, 1946; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Uphoff, Delta, 1954-1972; 12 items (Box 41)
    Biographical and personal data; Drosophila genetics; Mouse genetics; National Institutes of Health
  - Ursprung, Heinrich, 1965-1973; 12 items (Box 41)
    Biographical and personal data; Embryology, developmental genetics; Invitations; Recommendations -- Ursprung, Heinrich; Referee's report
  - Valentine, Alan, 1933-1947; 2 folders (Box 41)
    Business; Teaching; University of Rochester
    - Folder 1, 1933-1947; 16 items (Box 41)
    - Folder 2, 1947; 3 items (Box 41)
  - Vandenberg, Steven G., 1970-1972; 7 items (Box 41)
  - Van der Horst, Charles, 1971; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Van der Pas, Peter W., 1968; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Van Niel, C. B., 1949; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Varela, Holly E., 1966; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Vaudendries, R., 1930; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Verdoorn, Frans, 1941; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Verschuen, Mrs. V., 1969; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Voeller, Bruce R., 1959-1966; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Vogel, Friedrich, 1959-1970; 7 items (Box 41)
  - Voght, Walther, 1928-1929; 3 items (Box 41)
  - Vogt, Marguerite, 1929-1959; 6 items (Box 41)
  - Vollman, Rudolf F., 1970; 3 items (Box 41)
  - Vordemann, I. A., 1933; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Vorschuer, Frhr. v., 1958; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Waardenburg, P. J., 1953-1958; 3 items (Box 41)
  - Waddington, C. H., 1929-1965; 11 items (Box 41)
  - Waelsch, Salome G., 1968; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Wagner, Robert P., 1968; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Wahrman, Jacob, 1971; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Wahrman, Jacob. "Improvement of the diagnostic accuracy of mongolism at birth and of its various subtypes", 1968; 4 folders (Box 41)
    - Folder 1, 1968; 2 items (Box 41)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 41)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 1 item (Box 41)
    - Folder 4, n.d.; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Walen, Kirsten H., 1969-1970; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Walker, Frank A., 1970; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Walker, Norma Ford, 1957; 3 items (Box 41)
  - Walker, Sally, 1940-1941; 11 items (Box 41)
  - Walknowska, Janina, 1952-1967; 19 items (Box 41)
  - Wallace, Bruce, 1930-1950; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Wallace, Isabel K., 1942; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Walter, H., 1968; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Walters, James L., 1967; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Walters, Marta, 1970; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Wang, Chyan-Tzaw 1958, 1 item (Box 41)
  - Wangenheim, H. v., 1973; 3 items (Box 41)
  - Ward, Ritchie R., 1970; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Ward's Natural Science Establishment, Inc., 1939-1949; 44 items (Box 41)
  - Wardhane, Shyam D., 1973; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Warkany, Josef, 1960; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Warmke, Germaine L., 1947; 3 folders (Box 41)
    Biographical and personal data; Drosophila genetics; Holtfreter, Johannes; Teaching -- Colegio de Agricultura y Artes Mecanicas, University of Puerto Rico; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Warmke, Germaine L., 1947; 6 items (Box 41)
    - Warmke, Germaine L. "Studies on phenotypic expression..." (Thesis, Univ. of Rochester), 1947; 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Folder 1, 1947; 1 item (Box 41)
      - Folder 2, 1947; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Warmke, H. E., 1945; 5 items (Box 41)
  - Warren, Charles O., 1954; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Warren, D. C., 1945; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Warren, Katherine Brehme, 1958-1961; 6 items (Box 41)
  - Warren, Shields, 1953-1957; 3 items (Box 41)
  - Wasko, Carol, 1968; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Wasserman, Gerhard D., 1971-1972; 6 items (Box 41)
  - Watanabe, Saburo, 1941-1966; 3 items (Box 41)
  - Watkeys, Charles W., 1941; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Watterson, Ray, 1941-1946; 15 items (Box 41)
  - Weber, Wendell W., 1965-1969; 4 items (Box 41)
  - Webster, L. T., 1941; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Weet, Herbert S., 1942-1945; 6 items (Box 41)
  - Wei, Irene, 1964; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Weicker, H., 1961-1969; 6 items (Box 41)
  - Weinberg, Alvin M., 1965-1968; 6 items (Box 41)
    Committee activities; Drosophila genetics; Genetics; Hollaender, Alexander; Kimball, Richard Fuller; Molecular genetics; Mouse genetics; Oak Ridge National Laboratory; Radiation genetics
  - Weinstein, Alexander, 1968; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Weisbrot, David R., 1967; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Weiss, Paul, 1943; 1 item (Box 41)
  - Weisskopf, Viktor, 1946; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Weitkamp, Lowell, 1969; 2 items (Box 41)
  - Welch, J. Philip, 1967; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Wellensiek, S. J., 1928; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Welshons, William, 1954-1979; 4 folders (Box 42)
    Biographical and personal data; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Hollaender, Alexander; Iowa State University; Mouse genetics; Oak Ridge National Laboratory; Publication; Russell, William Lawson
    - Folder 1, 1954-1959; 7 items (Box 42)
    - Folder 2, 1959-1960; 6 items (Box 42)
    - Folder 3, 1961-1965; 3 items (Box 42)
    - Folder 4, 1965-1979; 9 items (Box 42)
  - Wendt, G. Gerhard, 1959-1969; 6 items (Box 42)
  - Weninger, Marg., 1964; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Wenrich, D. H., 1940; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Went, L. N., 1971; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Wesleyan University. Department of Biology, 1971; 4 items (Box 42)
  - West, Dennis E., 1972; 2 items (Box 42)
  - West Coast Allergy Society, 1965; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Westergaard, Mogens, 1970-1972; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Wetmore, Ralph H., 1946; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Wettstein, Diter von, 1954; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Wettstein, Fritz von, 1927-1925; 4 items (Box 42)
  - Whetcombe, Joanne, 1973; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Whissell, Dorothy. "Dosage compensation in man and mouse", 1965; 1 item (Box 42)
  - White, Michael, 1958-1964; 2 items (Box 42)
  - White, Winifred S., 1970; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Whiteley, Arthur H., 1970; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Whiting, Anna R., 1962-1968; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Whittier, John R., 1967-1969; 4 items (Box 42)
  - Whittinghill, Maurice, 1964-1970; 8 items (Box 42)
  - Whyte, L. L., 1960; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Wiaine (Mrs.), n.d.; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Wichler, C., n.d.; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Wiegert, Louis, 1968; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Wiener, Alexander S., 1943-1972; 3 folders (Box 42)
    Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Fisher, Ronald Aylmer; Genetics -- Nomenclature; Human genetics -- Blood groups; Mendel, Gregor; Publication; Recommendations -- Denell, Robert
    - Folder 1, 1943-1968; 29 items (Box 42)
    - Folder 2, 1968-1972; 24 items (Box 42)
    - Folder 3, 1949-1972; 7 items (Box 42)
  - Wiesner, Jerome B., 1961; 2 items (Box 42)
  - John Wiley and Sons, 1946-1954; 9 items (Box 42)
  - Willcox, O. W., 1950; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Williams, Carroll, 1947; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Williams, Gabriel, 1967-1974; 4 folders (Box 42)
    Biographical and personal data; Drosophila genetics; Teaching -- University of Lagos; Travel -- Nigeria; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Williams, Gabriel, 1967; 8 items (Box 42)
    - Williams, Gabriel. "Mesonotal, Wing and Pleural Cell Lineage", 1974; 3 folders (Box 42)
      - Folder 1, 1974; 1 item (Box 42)
      - Folder 2, 1974; 1 item (Box 42)
      - Folder 3, 1974; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Williams, Jesse Feiring, 1954; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Williams, P. H., 1968; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Williams, Roger J., 1947; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Williamson, John H., 1970; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Willier, Benjamin Harrison, 1933-1971; 2 folders (Box 42)
    Biographical and personal data; Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Dalton, Howard Clark; Danforth, Charles Haskell; Fellowships, assistantships -- University of Rochester; Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict; House, Verl L.; Invitations; Johns Hopkins University; MacKnight, Robert H.; National Academy of Sciences; Publication -- Analysis of Development; Publication -- Quarterly Review of Biology; Recommendations -- Bodenstein, Dietrich; Teaching; University of California, Berkeley; Wright, Sewall
    - Folder 1, 1933-1947; 28 items (Box 42)
    - Folder 2, 1951-1971; 11 items (Box 42)
  - Willier, Helen S. (Mrs. Benjamin Harrison Willier), 1975; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Willis, Susan, 1964; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Wilson, Edmund Beecher, 1929-1937; 5 items (Box 42)
    Boveri, Theodor; Cytogenetics; Navashin, Sergei Gavrilovich
  - Wilson, G. B., 1929-1939; 4 items (Box 42)
  - Winchester, A. M., 1957; 3 items (Box 42)
  - Winkler, Dieter, 1968; 2 items (Box 42)
  - Winkler, Hans, 1930; 1 item (Box 42)
  - Wistar Institute of Anatomy and Biology, 1949; 3 items (Box 42)